## **Brad West**

brad@bradonomics.com

#### **OVERVIEW**

For years I have specialized in JAMstack web development. Primarily building with Jekyll and hosting with CloudCannon

Last year I started working through The Pragmatic Studio's Ruby and Rails courses. After that I decided I'd build an Instapaper clone called Portholes, which you can view on GitHub. I'm now working my way through Michael Hartl's book, *The Ruby on Rails Tutorial*.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Web Developer — Niyom

May 2020 - Present

I worked as the primary Jekyll developer for a large financial company in Dallas, Texas. This included things like:

- Building array structures for the CloudCannon platform
- Creating Ruby Gem themes to separate concerns and improve site build times
- Built Ruby script to scrape data from old website
- Frontend tasks such as building a guided website walkthrough using ShepherdJS

#### Web Developer — Travel Tripper

July 2017 - January 2019

I worked as part of a remote team building Jekyll and WordPress sites. I did a bit of documentation writing and a bit of bash scripting when necessary. I traveled to India to help team members with build tools, train junior developers, etc.

#### A few highlights:

Built and maintained WCAG/ADA compliant websites

- Used Angular to display API data from booking engine
- I was also the resident Linux admin and wrote bash scripts for the rest of the team

## **Web Developer** — Chiang Mai, Thailand — *Iqlu*

March 2014 - March 2016

I worked with a designer to build custom websites for company clients. Most were converted from PSD and built on WordPress.

## **Network and Systems Support** — *Various Companies*

1999 - 2008

I worked almost ten years as a Network and Systems Administrator as an active duty Marine and for government contractors. I also worked in technical support roles for private companies such as Integra Telecom and public organizations such as Portland Public Schools.

I've condensed most of my work history into this "various roles" section as it was support roles and not development. I can reminisce about these employment experiences at your request.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Payap University — Chiang Mai, Thailand

2009 - 2011, 2013 - 2014

Computer Information Systems, Communications, Hospitality Management

## Ramkhamhaeng University — Bangkok, Thailand

2011 - 2012

**Mass Communications** 

## Navy Fleet Training Center — Norfolk, Virginia

2001

Defense Message System Administrator Course

# **Marine Corps Communication Electronics School** — 29 Palms, California 2000

UNIX Systems Administrator Course

# **Marine Corps Communication Electronics School** — **29** Palms, California 1999

Small Computer Systems Specialist Course (MOS: 4066)